Darragh Kavanagh

Naas, County Kildare, Ireland



darragh87@yahoo.co.uk



linkedin.com/in/darragh-kavanagh-8114a4181

Summary

A highly motivated Retail Manager with 12 years retail management experience. Enjoy a challenge and consistently achieve high standards and have exceeded company targets. Experience includes customer service, merchandising, cash management, stock control, goods in / goods out, training, disciplinary, staffing issues, health and safety and responsible for opening and closing the store.

Experience

PRIMARK Flagship Night Senior Department Manager

Primark

Jul 2019 - Present (1 year 8 months +)

- -In charge of 4 junior managers.
- -Training new managers
- overseeing 3 sales floor and 5 stock rooms
- -In charge of 25+team members on a nightly basics

FRIMARK Flagship Night Department Manager

Primark

Mar 2016 - Jul 2019 (3 years 5 months)

Sales and Commercial Focus - Maximising sales, opportunities and performance

Drive and monitor sales in my departments ensuring that all targets are met

Ensure all department sales reports are checked daily/weekly and action taken where appropriate

Using all available reports maintain a full knowledge of department sales figures, budgets and SPV (Selling Price Variance) to maximise performance

Mark down individual items of stock in line with company policy, in a timely manner and monitor to ensure sell through

Understand the market by monitoring the local area and competitor activity to maintain competitive advantage

Communicate and promote Primark's Corporate Social Responsibility policy

Stock Management - Managing stock file so as to minimise cost

Ensure stock levels are sufficient to maximise sales across department, through effective use of the Stock Replenishment System (PSR) system

Be fully aware of stock in your department and use available information resources to ensure stock is displayed in line with sales and that best sellers are promoted

Monitor the performance of new lines and replenish stock to ensure sufficient cover in your department to deliver maximum sales performance

Implement relevant systems and procedures to minimise stock loss and ensure it is within company limits

PRIMARK Department Manager

Primark

Jun 2015 - Mar 2016 (10 months)

People - Recruiting, leading and motivating team to achieve company standards

Optimise staff morale and promote a positive work environment whilst ensuring staff are fully aware of their obligations in relation to company policies

In conjunction with supervisors compile daily plans for staff coverage and rotas

Communicate with and work alongside staff and supervisors to achieve required results

Gain understanding of all areas of the store and company strategy

Develop management and people management skills

Work in conjunction with my store manager to achieve targets and timescales set in the Management Development Programme

Develop my own capability by using all Management resources to learn new systems and procedures

Merchandising – Delivering excellent visual standards

Ensure that high visual merchandising standards are sustained in line with the Store Operations Manual across the department and visual impact is optimised in order to attract sales

Ensure levels of stock are maintained and merchandised in line with company guidelines to maximise sales

Ensure department presentation, point of sale and ticketing is consistent and in line with legislative requirements and company policy and procedures

Carry out department inspections daily

PRIMARK Trainee Manager

Primark

Jun 2014 - Jun 2015 (1 year 1 month)

Operating Standards - Consistently deliver against company expectations and policy

Implement systems and procedures to maintain operational standards in line with the Store Operations Manual and all other procedural guidelines

Maintain standards throughout the day ensure recovery is completed daily

Ensure compliance with the company refund procedure and daily refund checks

Customer Service - Leading the team to deliver excellent customer service

Ensure staff are demonstrating excellent customer service standards at all times

In the event of a customer complaint or query I would react in a professional and courteous manner, elevating the issue to senior management where necessary

Ensure compliance with the company refund procedure and daily refund checks



Merchandiser

FMI Ireland

Feb 2014 - Jun 2014 (5 months)

- # Merchandising for LidI Stores
- # Working on own initiative
- # Merchandising for Coco Cola
- # Working as part of a team



Duty Manager

Dealz Ireland

Jul 2012 - Mar 2013 (9 months)

Security - Preventing company property loss, theft or abuse

Responsibility for holding store keys and being available for emergency callout

Ensure staff in the department are fully aware of and complying with company policies regarding security

Accountable for securing all cash, stock and property

Follow appropriate company policies regarding customer or staff theft

Comply with company procedures on staff searches

Environment, Health & Safety - Overall store responsibility for ensuring H&S standards are adhered to

Maintain an up- to-date understanding of relevant legislation to produce a safe working environment across your departments

Ensure all EHS records and documentation are maintained within company guidelines

Ensure compliance with legislation associated with fire prevention and the protection of people and property in the event of a fire

Accountable for staff being fully conversant and comply with Health & Safety at work provisions

Be alert to any potential hazards across your departments



Store Manager

Paul Byron Shoes

Feb 2012 - Jul 2012 (6 months)

Sales and Commercial Focus – Maximising sales, opportunities and performance

Drive and monitor sales figures and stock analysis across the sales floor through the utilisation of available information resources to ensure all targets are met

Ensure all markdowns are carried out in line with company policy in a timely manner and monitored to ensure sell through

Communicate effectively to ensure the management team are aware of sales targets, relevant budgets and priorities

Understand the market by monitoring the local area and competitor activity to maintain competitive advantage

Support the team to achieve the sales budget to maximise sales within each section

Liaise with the local town and Shopping Centre management with regard to local initiatives

Customer Service - Responsible for leading the team to deliver excellent customer service

Ensure management team and staff are familiar with and are demonstrating excellent customer service standards at all times

Manage customer issues and complaints in line with company standards and to ensure prevention of occurrence in the future

Assistant Store Manager

Paul Byron Shoes

Dec 2011 - Feb 2012 (3 months)

Customer Service - Responsible for leading the team to deliver excellent customer service

Ensure management team and staff are familiar with and are demonstrating excellent customer service standards at all times

Manage customer issues and complaints in line with company standards and to ensure prevention of occurrence in the future

Security - Preventing company property loss, theft or abuse

Responsibility for holding store keys and being available for emergency callouts

Support managers to ensure staff are fully aware of company policies regarding security

Responsible to the Store manager for delivering all cash control actions in accordance with company policy

Comply with company procedures in regard to staff searches

T Stockroom Supervisor

Ted Baker

Apr 2010 - Dec 2011 (1 year 9 months)

- # Accepting and checking of deliveries
- # Responsible for stock control
- # Daily walk through of stockrooms
- # Transfer of stock around the world

T Stockroom Assistant

Ted Baker

Sep 2009 - Apr 2010 (8 months)



Assistant Manager

Calvin Klein Jeans

Mar 2008 - Sep 2009 (1 year 7 months)

Achieving and maintaining high store standards

- # Responsible for achieving sales targets
- # Identify training and coaching needs for development
- # Delivering a high standard of customer service

Trainee Manager

Eurospar

Mar 2006 - Mar 2008 (2 years 1 month)

- # Responsibility for ATM control
- # Stock taking and Stock count
- # Complaint management
- # Time Management

Sales Assistant

Eurospar

May 2005 - Mar 2006 (11 months)

Education

Alison's.com (Online)

certificate, customer service training 2013 - 2013

Alison's.com (online)

dimploma, customer service 2013 - 2013

creative traning

Fetac level 4, office support skills 2013 - 2013 It, It apps,general office skills, customer service

colaiste chillian

1999 - 2005

Ailison.com (online)

Certificate, Retail Management: Stock, Psychology and Security Jan 2021 - Present

Skills

Great Organizer • Teamwork • Time Management • Delegate Management • Communication • English • Sales • Team Motivation • Customer Service • Cash Management